Email: klara.janouskova@fel.cvut.cz Nationality: Czech

#### **About**

I am currently pursuing a master's degree in computer science, majoring in computer vision. I am part of the Visual Recognition Group of my university, my research has focused on document analysis, most recently weakly supervised learning for text detection and recognition. Apart from machine learning and mathematics, I am interested in psychology and neuroscience.

### **Work experience**

#### Technion VISTA lab, Research Intern

September 2022 - October 2022

Czech-Israeli Innovation Internships. I am hosted by prof. Alex Bronstein, working with Chaim Basking, on the topic of weakly and self-supervised learning for image segmentation.

IBM Research - Zurich, Student Researcher

July 2021 - December 2021

Al Automation group, explainability. I am working on visual inspection for civil infrastructure.

Centre for Machine Perception, CTU Prague, Research Intern

2017 - now

2018 - now

2016 - now

Visual Recognition Group, working under the supervision of prof. Jiří Matas.

I worked on document analysis projects - scene-text region detection and document layout analysis. Currently, I am working on weakly supervised learning for text detection and recognition.

Computer Vision Center, UAB, Research Intern

July 2019 - September 2019

I worked on weakly supervised learning for text detection and recognition under the supervision of prof. Dimosthenis Karatzas.

**Applifting**, Ruby on Rails Backend Trainee developer

June 2016 - August 2016

I worked on project Yunoia, a social network for the game industry.

Startup that develops iOS, web and Android applications.

**Czechitas,** Volunteer
Teaching introductory level programming courses.

Non-profit organization that aims for higher tech literacy among women and youth.

**MoRoUS**, Organizer

Correspondence seminar for high school students organised by a group of volunteers from the Faculty of Electrical Engineering, CTU Prague.

#### **Education**

# Czech Technical University in Prague, Master of Science

September 2020 - now

Faculty of Electrical Engineering, major in Computer Vision (1.17/4 WGPA).

Courses: Statistical Machine Learning, Digital Image, Advanced Algorithms, Evolutionary Optimization Algorithms, Neurophysiology, Computer Vision Methods, Geometry of Computer Vision and Graphics, Combinatorial Optimization, Theory of Algorithms

**Czech Technical University in Prague**, Bachelor of Science

September 2017 - 2020

Faculty of Electrical Engineering, major in Informatics and Computer Science.

I graduated with honours (1.15/4 WGPA, rank 7), completing a minor degree in mathematics.

Bachelor thesis: Learning with Weak Annotations for Text in the Wild Detection and Recognition

CS: Solving Problems and other Games; Procedural Programming; Operating Systems; Database Systems; Parallel and Distributed Computing; Functional Programming; Recognition and Machine Learning, Object Design and Modelling

Math: Discrete Mathematics; Logic and Graphs; Linear Algebra; Mathematical Analysis I and II; Optimization; Information Theory and Coding; Advanced Analysis; Graph Theory; Numerical Analysis

Other: Philosophy

#### Universitat Politècnica de València,

September 2018 - January 2019

Erasmus+ at School of Informatics. I obtained the best possible score for Algorithms and 'Matrícula de Honor' (granted to up to 5% of the students provided they have obtained the 'Excellent' classification) for Probability and Statistics, Introduction to AI, and Languages, Automata and Grammars.

Courses: Language, automata and grammars; Introduction to Artificial Intelligence; Techniques, tools and applications of Artificial Intelligence, Probability and Statistics; Algorithms

#### **Publications**

Text Recognition - Real World Data and Where to find Them, Klára Janoušková, Lluis Gómez, Dimosthenis Karatzas, Jiří Matas; ICPR2020 (arxiv, youtube)

#### Languages

Native: Czech

Advanced: English (CAE certificate), Spanish (Título de Bachiller, Czech-Spanish high-school)

Intermediate: French Elementary: German

## **Technical skills**

**Work experience:** Python (OpenCV, scikit-learn, PyTorch), Ruby (Ruby on Rails) **School projects:** Java (Android), C (++), Lisp, Haskell, Matlab, Maple, Mathematica, HTML/CSS

## **Achievements**

#### **IBM Great Minds 2021 winner**

2021

https://www.zurich.ibm.com/greatminds/ - a competition for 3 to 6-month internships at one of the IBM Research Labs.

Dean's award for an outstanding bachelor's thesis.

2020

100<sup>th</sup> percentile in the SCIO National Comparative Exams in Mathematics

2017

The best result in the cohort. Criterion in the acceptance processes of many Czech universities.

## Open Informatics scholarship for talented girls

2017

A scholarship awarded to top-scoring students in the NCE in Mathematics.

#### **Personal interests**

When not reading, I enjoy sports (bouldering and windsurfing are my favourites lately) and showing a different perspective on the world through macro-photography.